前情提要
黑客軍團
是她丈夫  斯考特·諾爾斯
看來董事會已經審查過他了
那我們得盡快跟他們吃頓晚飯
黑客軍團
第一季 第五集
ZiMuZu
傾情奉獻
黑衣章魚X  不高興童鞋   showeryhe
翻譯
杏仁斯嘉麗   流水亦芳菲
ABCpril
翻譯
黑客草
薛定諤的貓
時間軸
Kallen
校對&特效
糊涂草
后期
你是不是餓得慌
顧問
somehacker
總監
草society
他想黑進鋼山的氣候控制系統
He wants to hack Steel Mountain's climate control system,
升高整個中心的溫度  毀掉所有磁帶
raise the facility's heat high enough to destroy all the tapes.
這就是我們要做的
This is what we're doing.
你們一走我就聯系我黑暗軍團的聯絡人
I'll hit up my Dark Army contact as soon as you take off.
你就這樣"聯系"世界上最危險的黑客團體嗎
You just gonna hit up the world's most dangerous hacker crew?
他掌握了我的銀行賬戶  奧利
He has my bank account, Ollie.
我們不能為此就感染眾安的網絡
We cannot just infect Allsafe's network because of this.
我會丟了工作的
I'll lose my job.
邪惡公司正在升級他們的安保協議
Evil Corp's upping their security protocol.
他們準備把所有數據的模擬備份
They are physically copying then shipping
復制轉運到各地
all the analog backups.
我們今天就得行動
We go up today.
我希望你能跟我一起在這里
I want you to be where you belong:
你屬于這里
here with me.
我現在在那兒就很開心
I think I'm happy where I am.
別讓我失望  好嗎
Don't let me down, okay?
那女孩是我的
That girl in there is mine.
維拉被抓和你有關系嗎
Did you have something to do with Vera getting busted?
他被控殺人罪了  你知道嗎
He's on murder charges, do you know that?
這是我的計劃  我進去
It's my plan. I'll go in.
你也許能瞞過這些呆子
You might be able to hide it from these nerds,
但我一眼就能認出癮君子
but I know a junkie when I see one.
我是一個人
I'm alone.
不  不是的
No, you're not.
我哪都不會去的  孩子
I'm not going anywhere, kiddo.
我也希望能給你帶來好消息  費南多
I wish I had better news for you, Fernando,
但這次來不是告訴你出獄有望的
but this isn't the you're-getting-out meeting.
我能帶進來的就這么多了
This is only as much as I could carry.
地檢那里還有更多
The D.A. has more.
能判多久
How long this gonna be?
很多年
We're talking years.
你開玩笑呢吧
Yo, you playing?
你把我們的人撈出來
You get our people out.
這就是你的工作
That's your use to us.
他們掌握了充分的證據
They have a solid case.
每一個他們指控你的罪名
For every charge they're gonna lay on you,
都有這么一個文件夾  你的推特和圖片分享
they have these binders, your twitters, your instagram.
你說他們破解不了這暗語的
You said they wouldn't figure this shit out.
他們破不了  老兄
They can't, brah.
我跟你說  這暗語絕對安全  維哥
I'm telling you, it was airtight, V.
兩位  這可不是《模仿游戲》
Fellas, this isn't the Imitation Game.
你們的密碼沒那么保密
The code here is not that complicated.
再說了  是誰讓你把生意
Besides, who told you to put your business
弄到社交網絡上去的
anywhere near social media?
當然是我那靈光的老弟了
My aspirational little brother.
你知道去年我們省了多少錢嗎
You know how much money we saved last year?
整個生意的效率都大幅提高了
Made our whole operation way more efficient.
我們很小心
We were careful.
你們把每一筆交易都發到推特上了
You tweeted about every transaction your business was involved in.
簡直就是小心的反義詞
That is the opposite of careful.
難怪會有匿名線報把你舉報了
It's no wonder an anonymous tip turned you in.
誰舉報的
Who called in the tip?
不知道  所以才叫"匿名線報"
This is what is meant by anonymous.
現在是覆水難收了
It is now spilled milk.
信息全都泄露出去了
The information got out,
現在后果很嚴重
and now they're coming down hard.
對方無意提供檢控協議
There's no plea on the table.
他們會指控你一級謀殺
They're gonna lay murder one on you.
反正我也沒打算認罪
I ain't pleading anyway.
凡人不能給我判刑
Men can't sentence me.
只有宇宙能審判我
That is a cosmic responsibility.
會有人為此付出代價的
Someone's gonna get hurt for this.
這樣我們才能跟宇宙扯平
That's how we get square with the universe.
費南多  我們得想想應訴策略了
Fernando, we need to discuss strategy.
你可不會希望被關進重罪監獄的
You don't want supermax.
當然  當然
Naw, naw.
如果他們把我扔進監獄
If they lock me up,
扔進哪一種監獄也無所謂了
the kind of door they close don't matter.
原來是你
So that's you.
原來你是這樣的人
That's who you are.
我了解你了
I know you.
借過
Excuse me.
抱歉  抱歉  我已經買過了
Pardon me. Pardon me. I already paid.
就是想跟店家道個謝
Just want to pay my respects.
多謝  多謝
Thank you. Thank you.
抱歉  抱歉
Ooh, I'm sorry, man. Sorry.
就是想來給個好評
Just want to pay my compliments.
咖啡很好喝  服務很周到
Hey, excellent coffee, fantastic service.
犒勞犒勞自己吧
Buy yourself something nice.
鋼山公司
員工
系統連接成功
成功讀寫數據塊
鋼山
Steel Mountain.
我們想黑的這家數據安全中心
We're trying to penetrate a data security facility
其宣傳語是...
whose tagline literally is...
鋼山公司  牢不可破
世上根本沒有牢不可破的東西
Nothing is actually impenetrable.
這種地方這樣夸口  實際也幾乎牢不可破
A place like this says it is, and it's close,
但這里畢竟還是人蓋的
but people still built this place.
只要你黑對了人
And if you can hack the right person,
突然間
all of a sudden,
你就擁有了一個威力巨大的惡意軟件
you have a piece of powerful malware.
人總是最佳突破口
People always make the best exploits.
絕大多數人都不難黑
I've never found it hard to hack most people.
只要你傾聽他們  觀察他們
If you listen to them, watch them,
他們的缺點就像
their vulnerabilities are like
釘在頭頂的霓虹燈一樣
a neon sign screwed into their heads.
莫布利貪吃
Mobley's a glutton.
他沒法控制吃東西的欲望
He lacks discipline from his urges.
可別招來蟲子  萬一傳染什么病呢
I don't want to get bugs. They spread disease.
羅梅洛是個萬事通  總是疑神疑鬼
Romero is a know-it-all and a hypochondriac.
比爾·哈珀  一樓銷售員
比爾·哈珀
一樓銷售員
比爾·哈珀是我們的第一個突破口
Bill Harper is our first exploit.
他核實你身份時不會看得太細
He isn't gonna give the search much scrutiny.
他能帶我們進一樓
He'll get us to Level 1,
但是想上二樓就不能靠比爾了
but Bill is not gonna be able to get us to Level 2.
而我們得上到二樓
And we need to get to Level 2.
你得要求和他的主管溫蒂談
You're gonna ask to speak to his supervisor, Wendy.
溫蒂·蓋勒格  客服主管
她會帶我們去我們想去的地方
She'll get us to exactly where we need to be.
然后我們這邊想辦法支開她
Then we'll be able to get rid of her from the van.
之后你就把樹莓派
After that, you connect the Raspberry Pi
接到氣候控制系統上  后面的就輕而易舉了
to the climate control system, and Bob's your uncle.
這樣我們就能聽見你說話  你也能聽見我們
Now we can hear you, and you can hear us.
至于機器人先生
Mr. Robot?
他的缺點就是他完全是個瘋子
His flaw is he's absolutely insane.
病態的瘋
We're talking clinical.
如果有人問"你朋友跳橋  你會跟著跳嗎"
When they say, "If your friends jump off a bridge, would you?"
他會毫不猶豫地跳下去
He would, without hesitation,
就為了證明自己
just to prove something.
他進去的話  可能會把整個建筑炸毀
He goes in there, he's liable to blow the whole place up,
就像他之前想做的那樣
just like he wanted to in the first place.
你不需要再過一遍資料  看看地圖什么的
Sure you don't want to look over the info and the map again?
我能行
I got it.
那好  007  咱們攪他個天翻地覆吧
Okay, James Bond, let's go mess their shit up.
當然我也有安全漏洞
Yes, I also have security flaws.
我不喜歡外出
I don't like being outside.
我太依賴嗎啡了
I liked morphine too much.
賽皮奧先生
Mr. Sepiol?
我在跟你說話
I'm talking to you right now,
而你根本不存在
and you don't exist.
薩姆·賽皮奧
Sam Sepiol?
先生
Sir?
叫你呢  艾略特
That's you, Elliot.
好
Okay.
抱歉讓您久等了
So sorry you had to wait.
您也看見了  我們要接待的太多了
As you can see, there's always a lot of bustle here.
我能為您做什么
How can I help you today?
你就是想參觀  別多說
you need a tour. Don't elaborate.
參觀
A tour.
好吧
Okay.
我想前臺應該告訴您了
I'm sure they told you at reception
想參觀的話需要提前預約
that we--we require appointments for tours.
我們主管還狠狠地強調過這一點
My supervisor gives us all a hard time about that.
我是薩姆·賽皮奧
I'm Sam Sepiol.
你最好上網搜搜我
You should look me up.
好吧
Okay.
有點太直白  不過我們能應付
A little inelegant, but we can work with it.
這樣吧
Tell you what.
讓貴公司聯系我們的開戶員
Have your company call over to new accounts,
我們周末之前就能給您安排好
and we can set something up later this week.
找比爾·哈珀
Ask for Bill Harper.
他們知道去哪找我
They'll know where to find me.
聽著  比爾
listen, Bill.
你以為你上司現在對你就夠狠了嗎
You think your boss gives you a hard time now?
我要是甩手走人了
You're gonna get a really hard time
你會見識到什么叫狠的
right after I walk out of here.
我非今天不可  比爾
I'm not rescheduling, Bill.
只要我走人  就絕不會再回來
When I walk out that door, I'm never coming back.
這全怨你  比爾
That's your ass, Bill.
我真覺得你該上網搜一搜我
I really think you should look me up.
程序不是這么走的
It--it just doesn't work like that.
很抱歉  先生
I'm sorry, sir.
您保重
You take care, okay?
我要出來了  根本不管用
I'm coming out. It's not working.
能行的
It's gonna work.
堅持住
Hang in there.
我表現得太詭異了
I was being too weird.
就跟其他科技產業的億萬富翁一樣
Just like every other tech billionaire.
放慢腳步  肯定能行的
Slow your roll. It's gonna happen.
怪不得維基百科上的信息從來都不準確
It's no wonder Wikipedia is never accurate.
薩姆·賽皮奧
誰都可以編輯詞條
Anyone can edit them.
也不是所有人啦
Well, not anyone.
莫布利這種技術宅憑借他這些年兩萬條的編輯
Nerds like Mobley built a lot of credit over the years
建立了不少信譽值
with his 20,000 edits.
首次公開募股后  賽皮奧賺得170億美元
但人們還是相信維基
And still people trust it,
從全世界像莫布利這樣的人那里獲取信息
beholden to all the Mobleys of the world for their information.
賽皮奧先生
Mr. Sepiol?
Mr. Sepiol!
有個好消息告訴你
I have some good news.
停下  快停下
Stop it. Stop it.
你能不能先別收拾東西了  給我五分鐘時間
Can you stop packing for, like, five minutes?
咱們像成年人一樣把事情解決了
Can we just hash this out like adults?
我愛你
I love you.
你都不知道你為什么要哭
You don't even know why you're crying.
我們結婚吧
Let's get married.
奧利  別說了
Ollie, will you please stop?
安吉拉  你不能就這樣放棄我們的感情
Angela--Angela, you can't just give up on us like this.
你仔細考慮過嗎
I mean, have you even thought this through?
你要怎么辦  去新澤西州和你爸住嗎
What are you gonna do, go live with your dad in Jersey?
拜托
Come on.
你這是在自毀前程
You're ruining your life.
或許吧
Maybe,
不過我也毀了你的前程
but I also ruined yours.
你為什么會有我的工作證
Why do you have my work ID?
你...
Did you--
你...你是不是
Did you-- do you--do you--
你知道這會有什么后果嗎
Do you know what's gonna happen?
這后果會很嚴重的  我會告訴他們的
There will be fallout from this, and I'm gonna tell them--
我用了你的電腦  你想怎么說隨你
I used your computer, so tell them whatever you want.
你是認真的嗎
Are you serious?
你有沒有想過這對我會有什么影響
Did you even think about how this would affect me?
我想過
I did.
我來描述一下這地方有多大
Here's an idea of how big this place is.
我們有自己的消防局  就在這棟樓里
We have our own fire department, inside the building,
專為我們服務
Just for us.
有了消防局怎么能沒有消防車
And you can't have a fire department without a fire truck,
沒有路又沒法開車
and you can't have a fire truck without roads.
這些我們全有  就在這棟樓里
We have all of that, inside.
試想一下吧
Imagine that.
數據管理
數據存儲
艾略特  該甩掉比爾了
Elliot, now's the time we get rid of bill.
這里有好多信息
There's so much information...
好了  該卷起袖子來真的了
Okay, we're gonna need to roll up our sleeves here.
要叫他主管來  你就必須擊垮比爾
You have to destroy Bill in order to get to a supervisor.
這里有一個保險庫  占地1.8萬平方米
There's one vault in here that's 200,000 square feet.
都趕上購物中心了
That's the size of a shopping mall,
這才只是一個保險庫的大小
and that's just one.
比爾  那些巨型保險庫在哪
Bill, where are those giant vaults?
在二樓  不過這不屬于參觀范圍
Oh, they're on level 2, but that's not part of the tour.
連我都無權進入
Even I don't have authorization.
他不會帶你去吃冰淇淋的
He's not gonna take you for ice cream.
你必須解決掉他
He has to go away.
這個計劃里容不得比爾
There's no place in this plan for Bill.
從這里一直走下去
Now, right down here--
你還好嗎  先生
Everything okay, sir?
我們得把比爾大卸八塊
We need to tear Bill down piece by piece.
你得把他的笑容從他那張傻臉上抹去
You need to wipe that smile off of his stupid face.
先生  你還好嗎
Sir, are you okay?
你怎么不說話
You're not-- you're not saying anything.
下狠手  艾略特
Dig into him, Elliot.
你是最適合做這事的  艾略特
You of all people can do this, Elliot.
你清楚被人輕視是什么感覺
You know how it feels when someone makes you small.
你懂得內心深處的恐懼被暴露時
You understand what happens when someone exposes
會發生什么
the thing you fear most about yourself.
你說呀
Answer me!
回答我
站起來
Get up.
給我站起來
Just get up!
我討厭你
I hate you.
你什么也不是
You're nothing.
你真沒用
You're worthless.
想想吧  比爾
Think about it, Bill.
想什么
Think about what?
如果你死了
If you died,
會有人在乎嗎
would anyone care?
他們真的會在乎嗎
Would they really care?
沒錯  或許他們會哭上一天
Yeah, maybe they'd cry for a day,
但面對現實吧
but let's be honest.
根本沒人會在乎
No one would give a shit.
他們不會在乎
They wouldn't.
那幾個覺得自己必須要出席你葬禮的人
The few people that would feel obligated to go to your funeral
很可能心里也會不痛快
would probably be annoyed,
而且很早就離場
and leave as early as possible.
那就是你
That's who you are.
你的本質
That's what you are.
沒人在乎你
You're nothing to anyone,
一個都沒有
to everyone.
想想吧  比爾
Think about it, Bill.
因為如果你真去想
'cause if you do,
如果你肯去想
if you let yourself...
你就會知道我說的是實話
You'll know I'm telling you the truth.
所以別再浪費我的時間了
So instead of wasting any more of my time,
去給我叫個管事的人來
I need you to go call someone that matters,
因為  比爾...
because, Bill...
你是無名小輩
You don't.
我這就...
I'll...
我這就聯系主管
I'll call my supervisor.
所以說  比爾·哈珀是絕佳突破口
And that's why Bill Harper is a perfect exploit,
威廉·哈珀鋼山一樓銷售員
會為了業績不顧一切地打破規程
desperate enough for the business to break protocol
工作經歷           銷售團隊
批量銷售
放我進來
and let me in.
比·哈珀47個發布  5個粉絲  536個關注
非常寂寞  容易擊垮
Lonely enough to break.
派一位主管來一樓3區
I need a supervisor in L1-S3.
收到
Copy that.
不要道歉
Don't apologize.
馬上就成功了  你表現得很好
You're almost there. You did great.
溫蒂一過來  我們就給她發短信
Once Wendy gets there, we'll send her a text
說她懷孕的妻子要生了
letting her know her pregnant wife is in labor.
溫蒂·蓋
她離開后  你應該能有足夠時間
Once she leaves, that should give you enough time
去植入樹莓派  明白嗎
to plant the Pi, you dig?
楚迪·戴維斯  客戶主管
Trudy Davis, Accounts Supervisor.
這兒有什么問題嗎
Is there a problem here?
-賽皮奧先生...  -楚迪
- Mr. Sepiol is asking... - Trudy?
要求見一位職位比我高的人
for someone more senior than me.
我這里沒有您的名字
I don't seem to have your name.
我是薩姆·賽皮奧
I'm Sam Sepiol?
-你是在問我嗎  -楚迪  楚迪
- Is that a question? - Trudy? Trudy?
溫蒂到哪去了
Where's Wendy?
我們只準備了溫蒂  溫蒂死哪去了
We only prepped for Wendy. Where the hell is Wendy?
其實  我找溫蒂
I need Wendy, actually.
你怎么認識溫蒂的  她今天沒來上班
And how do you know Wendy? She didn't come in today.
溫蒂·蓋勒格
看誰出現了
你需要什么  賽皮奧先生
What is it that you need, Mr. Sepiol?
我想去二樓參觀
I would love a tour of Level 2.
我不知道他都跟您說什么了
I don't know what you've been told,
但我們禁止那樣做
but we don't allow that.
我送您出去  你可以走了  比爾
I'll see you out. You can go, Bill.
請跟我去大堂
Follow me to the lobby.
楚迪·戴維斯
這女人是個幽靈
This woman's a ghost.
這些都不是她
None of these are her.
沒有臉書  沒有鄰客音
No Facebook, no LinkedIn.
她結婚30年了
She's been married for 30 years.
我們只有她丈夫的手機號碼
All we have is her husband's cell phone number.
網上也沒有他的照片
He doesn't even have a picture online.
沒有愛好  沒有孩子
No hobbies, no kids,
沒有信用問題  沒有性怪癖
no credit problems, no weird sex stuff.
房子已付清
House paid off.
我得...我得思考
I need-- I need to-- I need to think.
電梯快來了
The elevator's almost here.
對  你按下按鈕就會這樣
Yes, that's how they work when you press the button.
好吧
Okay.
人們都只是人  對嗎
People-- people are all just people, right?
說到底  人人都一樣
When it gets down to it, everyone's the same.
他們有喜歡的東西
They love something.
有渴望的東西  有害怕的東西
They want something. They fear something.
細節確實有用  但細節改變不了
Specifics help, but specifics don't change
每個人脆弱的一面
the way that everyone is vulnerable.
它只改變我們如何觸及他們脆弱的一面
It just changes the way that we access those vulnerabilities.
發送短信至
我得走了  抱歉
I-I have to go. I'm sorry.
我得回辦公室去
I need to go to my office.
前臺會送您出去的
Reception will see you out.
你做了什么
What'd you do?
我偽造了一條她丈夫發的短信
I spoofed a text from her husband.
我給你打過電話
但是打不通
我在醫院
我們一直害怕的事成真了
數據管理
數據存儲
是掌紋掃描儀
It's a palm print scanner.
從電梯里出來
Get out of there.
有一扇手動開關的門
There's one door manually locked.
是消防應急門  但我想你能撬開
It's a fire code thing, and I think you can pick it.
在哪
Where?
你在一樓向北走  門在走廊盡頭
It's at the end of the hallway if you're heading north on L1.
樓梯
通往
停車場
樓梯不通往二樓
The stairs don't go to Level 2.
是通往停車場
They go to a parking lot.
你在大樓的另一邊  方向完全錯了
You're on the complete wrong side of the building.
你得折回去
You're gonna have to double back
走你來時的門  快點跑
and go through the door you came in and make a run for it.
艾略特...
Elliot...
我就說我看見你了
I thought I saw you.
你來這兒干什么
What are you doing here?
謝謝您
Thank you.
期待您再次光臨烤翅盛會餐廳
Y'all come back to Wingstravaganza.
這一點非常重要...
Okay, real important...
烤翅盛會餐廳的名字就是烤翅加盛會
Wingstravaganza means wings and extravaganza.
你知道盛會是什么意思嗎
Do you know what extravaganza means?
知道  就是大事件
Yep, it's a big deal.
答對了
You got it.
你看起來有點緊張  你激動嗎
You look nervous. Are you excited?
-激動  -好的
- Oh, yeah. - Okay.
你這周都跟著我  但別擔心
So you'll shadow me for the week, but don't sweat it.
這和其他服務員工作一樣
It's like every other server job.
其實我之前從沒當過服務員
Well, I've actually never been a waitress before.
這對我來說是個新的開始
This is kind of like a new beginning for me.
你之前是做什么的
What were you doing before?
藥物銷售
Pharmaceutical sales.
不錯啊
Fancy.
你肯定掙了很多  后來怎么了
You must have made bank. What happened?
奧巴馬醫改咯
Oh, um, just, you know, Obamacare.
歡迎來到鋼山數據中心
Welcome to Steel Mountain's data center.
本機構達到鉆石級要求
Our facility meets diamond specifications
設計和建造均達到十級標準
and features a tier 10 certified build and design,
為您的數據需求提供安全堅固的堡壘
providing you with a safe, rock-solid fortress for your data needs.
我們整個機構都采用綜合安全措施
All of our facilities implement comprehensive security measures...
他們說我用力過猛  我說正是如此
They say I'm overdoing it, and I say exactly.
沒錯
So yeah.
艾略特
Elliot.
-見到你很高興  -我也是
- Nice meeting you. - You too.
-代我向尊夫人問好  -好的
- Tell your wife I said hi. - I will.
我剛握手的那幾位
Those men I just shook hands with,
是真主黨和伊斯蘭國的投資人
financiers of Hezbollah and ISIS.
別盯著他們看
I wouldn't stare.
他知道我會來這兒嗎
Did he know I was gonna be here?
他知道我來這兒干什么嗎
Does he know why I'm here?
媽的  他會殺了我的
Shit, he's gonna kill me.
你剛剛說什么
As you were saying?
只是例行數據處理檢測
Uh, just a routine data process check.
眾安經常這么干
Allsafe does them all the time.
可他們為什么派你來
But why would they send you?
這種事通常都由
That type of thing isn't usually handled
工程師來處理  不是嗎
by the engineers, is it?
我們的工作經常重疊
We've been overlapping a lot in our duties.
出于預算考慮
Budget reasons.
看來我們今天都決定在公司外工作
It seems we both had the idea to work off-site today.
稱其為巧合好了
Let's call this fortuitous.
跟我一起吃午飯嗎
Join me for lunch?
好啊
S-sure.
反正我也得吃午飯
I eat lunch.
看來你和我們是一樣的啊
So you are like the rest of us.
來吧
Come.
他被困住了
He got owned, man.
我們得走了
We got to go.
我們哪也不去
We're not going anywhere.
這不影響什么
This changes nothing.
你想吃什么  艾略特
What can I get you, Elliot?
這里東西很多
Have a lot of things here.
他有一個弱點
He has a vulnerability.
他是個自大的蠢貨  還引以為傲
He's an arrogant prick, and he's proud of it.
他在乎你對他的看法
He cares what you think about him,
雖然他可能也討厭自己這樣
even though he probably hates that he does.
提利爾·威利克最大的優勢就是他的狂妄自大
Tyrell Wellick's greatest asset is his hubris,
但這也是他的破綻  你的突破口
but it's also his flaw, and that's your exploit.
...不錯哦
Would be nice.
你就在這兒吃
You eat here?
這地方
This place?
你就打這個算盤  激怒他
Is that your plan, to piss him off?
等下  等等
No, wait, man. Wait.
二樓  貴賓休息室
記著  艾略特
Now remember, Elliot,
到了二樓你會失去我們的信號
you'll lose our signal on level 2.
艾略特
Elliot.
艾略特  聽到就說句話
Elliot, say something if you can hear us.
你會大老遠跑來真下功夫
I'm impressed you came all the way out here.
眾安完了  但你不肯讓它倒閉
Allsafe is finished, but you won't let it die.
我們一樣
We're the same.
我們是完美主義者
We're perfectionists.
那位服務員  我看他在這里干了...7年了
I've seen our waiter here for the last... seven years.
肯定五十多歲了  可能有孩子
Must be in his 50s, maybe has kids,
離異  再婚  又生了孩子
divorced, second wife, more kids.
我不禁好奇
And I wonder,
他是怎么想自己的
what must he think of himself?
他的人生就是如此  年薪三萬元
His life's potential reached at a 30-grand-a-year salary,
一輛經濟型轎車  貸款還沒付清
an economy car he still owes money on,
一間雙臥公寓
two-bedroom apartment,
子女撫養費  優惠券
child support, coupons.
我忍受不了
I couldn't bear it,
這種生活
a life like that.
這種平凡小人物的生活
The life of an ordinary cockroach
其最大的價值就是為我端沙拉
whose biggest value is to serve me salad.
我去下洗手間
I have to go to the bathroom.
戒斷反應又開始了
Goddamn withdrawals again.
還是因為提利爾·威利克
Or is it Tyrell Wellick?
他在玩兒我嗎
Is he toying with me?
我們這演的哪一出
What kind of game are we playing?
我是他的惡意軟件嗎
Am I his malware?
我得洗把臉
I had to wash my face.
這里讓人
Hard to breathe...
難以呼吸
here.
我知道是你陷害了泰瑞·科比
I know you framed terry colby.
我沒有
I-I didn't.
你父親死之前在邪惡公司工作
Your father worked at Evil Corp before he died.
公共記錄里有記載
That's a matter of public record.
我不打算告發你  如果你正這么想的話
I'm not turning you in, if that's what you're thinking.
我甚至連證據都沒有
I don't even have proof,
而且就算我有  我也不在乎
and even if I did, I don't care.
我只想掌握你的軟肋
Just wanted to know your weakness.
現在我掌握了
Now I do.
復仇
Revenge.
好平凡
How ordinary.
就像我們的服務員
Just like our waiter.
不過即便是那些杰出人士
But even extraordinary people,
而我相信你就是這種人
and I believe you are,
也會受到普通人陳腐思想的影響
are driven by human banalities.
可惜  眾人皆凡人
And unfortunately, we're all human.
當然了  除了我
Except me, of course.
我開玩笑的  艾略特
I'm joking, Elliot.
好好享受回家的漫漫長路
Enjoy your long drive back home.
我會坐直升機返回紐約
I'm having a helicopter take me back to new york.
保重  艾略特
You take care, Elliot.
氣夢軟件公司
去社會
你誤會了
誤會什么
去社會被踢出
你已被禁
不  搞什么
No. Bullshit.
拜托  搞什么飛機
Dude, bullshit!
-他們說什么了  -我不知道
- What did they say? - Oh, I don't know.
基本上就是說他們是一群沒種的混蛋
Basically that they're a bunch of dickless assholes.
-你去哪  -解決問題
- Where are you going? - To fix it.
沒有別人會去了
No one else is going to.
達琳  等等
Darlene, wait.
我真覺得你不該繼續逼迫他們了
I really don't think you should keep pushing them.
這么跟你說吧
Put it this way.
我要么解決問題  要么跟他們撕逼
Either I'm fixing this or breaking it.
看他們想怎樣
Their call.
甜心
Hi, pumpkin.
爸爸
Hey, daddy.
你怎么沒去上班
Why aren't you at work?
我和奧利分手了
I broke up with Ollie.
我知道
I know.
剛和他通完電話
Just got off the phone with him.
快進來
Come on.
他不停哭訴
He was sobbing.
讓我轉告你一些話
He wanted me to tell you something like,
"我會永遠愛你
"I'll always love you.
請回到我身邊"
Please come back."
還有  他說會學著諒解你
Oh, and he can learn to forgive you.
老天
Jesus.
你怎么說
What did you say?
我說我早就覺得你該跟他分手了
I told him I thought you should've broken up with him a long time ago
然后就把電話掛了
and hung up on him.
好啊
Nice.
他的話什么意思啊
What did he mean, anyway?
就是工作...
Just normal work and...
還有錢的事
money stuff.
對了  他還出軌了
And, well, he cheated on me,
還有這個
so there's that.
出軌這事  我一點也不驚訝
Well, the cheating part, I'm not surprised.
不是想讓你更難受  親愛的  但是拜托
Not trying to make you feel bad, honey, but come on.
那小子就是個混蛋
The kid's a douchebag.
-至于錢  -爸爸  別
- As for the money... - Dad, no.
我會借你些錢  供你進行職業發展
I'll float you some money for professional development.
爸爸
Dad--
就當是貸款
Call it a loan,
但別還我
but do not pay me back.
而且你還得住下  通勤上班
And you'll stay here and commute
直到攢夠錢再找一間公寓
until you can save for an apartment.
我不能逼你那么做
I can't make you do any of that.
你沒逼我
And you didn't.
我想這么做
It's what I want.
你餓嗎
Are you hungry?
-嗯  -別  坐著
- Yeah. - No, no. Sit, sit, sit, sit.
坐好
Relax.
想吃什么
What would you like?
你不用給我做飯啦  爸爸
You don't need to cook for me, dad.
法式吐司  這就來
French toast coming up!
這白癡要害我們遲到了
那我們就遲到唄  讓他們等
我見過他嗎
肯定是沒留下什么印象
是喜歡談酒的那個嗎
她呢
你老問她做什么
因為我還不知道她想要什么  這讓我緊張
別慌
這應該很簡單  他們幸福  滿足  似乎無欲無求
所以我才緊張
對這種人我們沒什么辦法  而且  我也不信真是這樣
不是每個人都像你那么不開心  親愛的
而且  即使他們真的很滿足
或是無欲無求  他們也會有所欲求的
你只需要奪走他們已有的
他們為什么退出了
Why are they backing out?
這是圖書館
This is a library.
你想說那事  上實時聊天去
You want to discuss that, go back to the irc island.
他們把我拉黑了
They banned me from the channel!
怎么回事
What happened?
我們拿下鋼山了
We just owned Steel Mountain.
我們做到我們的部分了  十分順利
We did our part, and it went perfect.
得了  我們都知道那種事不可能完全順利
Come on, we both know that shit didn't go perfect.
那也無所謂了  他們不干了
Well, it doesn't matter! They called it off.
我們做到了我們這邊
We pulled our side together,
你們那邊卻沒事人一樣的不干了
and your side called it off like it was nothing.
你已經得到回答了
You got your answer.
去告訴你伙計白玫瑰  別那么慫
You better tell your pal WhiteRose to stop being a pussy
有點膽
and start growing a pair
我們可沒時間瞎胡鬧
because we don't have time to dilly-dally around--
你現在還要明目張膽地說這事了
And now you're gonna talk about this in the world?
你在不在乎被人聽到啊
Do you even care who hears you?
面對現實吧  達琳
Face it, Darlene.
結束了
It's over.
放棄吧
Walk away.
我不能帶著這種結果回去見我的人
I can't go back to my people with that.
告訴我為什么
Tell me why.
你說過黑暗軍團會支持我們的
You said the Dark Army was with us on this.
就我們倆說說
Between us?
我又不會去發推特
I'm not about to goddamn tweet about it.
你們控制鋼山之前他們就退出了
They were out before you ever got to Steel Mountain.
我不知道為什么  他們只說了這么多
I don't know why. That's all they said to me.
我知道你下了決心
I know you had your heart set,
但這次真的
but for real this time,
放棄吧
just let it go.
-我需要席位  -不是吧
- I need seats mostly. - No.
我覺得在政府工作肯定很刺激
I imagine it must be exciting to work in government.
就像間諜電影里那樣
It's like a spy movie.
你能讀我的秘密電郵嗎
Can you read my secret emails?
不能
Mm, no.
我的工作主要是處理文件和手續工作
My job is mostly paperwork and bureaucracy.
他們總想要科技尚達不到的東西
They always want more than the technology allows.
我根本沒時間偷看你的秘密電郵
I don't even have time to read your secret emails.
這對我只是暫時的
But it's a stopgap for me.
我待不住
I'm restless.
總想換點花樣
I'm always itching for something else.
她換過不少呢
There have been a lot of something elses.
我們都是
For both of us.
在這之前  我在一家非政府組織工作
Before this, I worked at an ngo,
再之前在微軟干了一年
and before that, I worked at Microsoft for a year,
簡直度日如年
which felt like a decade.
你家真漂亮
Your place is beautiful.
我真想說謝謝
I wish I could take the compliment.
但裝飾是斯考特做的
The decorating is Scott's domain.
-是嗎  -是啊
- Oh, really? - Yes.
-不錯啊  -嗯
- Very nice. - Yeah.
古董都是哪里的
Where's all the-- the antiques from?
是...
They're--
他們要找你做首席技術官啊
So they tapped you for CTO, yes?
別那么驚訝
Don't be surprised.
應該說是懷疑
Suspicious is more accurate.
我還在想你為什么安排這頓晚餐呢
I was beginning to wonder why you set this dinner.
這世上只有4個人
Four people in the world
知道這事
know about my conversations.
但你卻不知怎么也知道了
Somehow you're number five.
那我正是你需要的副手人選
Then I'm exactly what you need in a right hand.
原來是為了這個
So that's what this is about.
每件事的背后不是都有個目的嗎
Isn't everything about something?
我們在考慮  是不是兒童防護的
Like, we were thinking about, is it--is it babyproof?
是啊  這的確是要考慮
Ah, yeah, that's-- that's a consideration.
如果你是我
If you were me,
會信任你做副手嗎
would you trust you as your right hand?
如果我是你
If I were you,
都不會放我進門
I wouldn't have even let me in the house.
是我
Hey, it's me.
現在方便嗎
Is now a good time?
嗯
Yeah.
我在我的新工作這兒
I'm at my new job.
怎么樣了
How's it going?
老實說  好難啊
Seriously, it's hard as hell,
不過  我慢慢掌握了
but I am getting the hang of it.
起初  把番茄醬倒在一起我弄了半天
At first, it took me, like, years to marry ketchups,
但是呢  我高價賣雞尾酒是個好手
but it turns out I'm amazing at upselling expensive cocktails.
這我不奇怪
I'm not surprised.
拼外賣單時
And then when I have to put together to-go orders,
發現跟裝搖頭丸很像  我做得可專業了
it's like bagging molly, so I'm, like, kind of an expert.
你怎么樣
How are you?
我挺好
I'm good.
是啊  這話我從沒聽你說過呢
Wow, I've never heard you say a sentence like that before, ever.
我今天做了我必須做的
I did what I had to do today.
如果你今晚在
Well, if you're around tonight,
過來跟我說說吧
come over and tell me about it, okay?
我得掛了
I got to go.
嗯  再見
Okay, bye.
你似乎很懂酒啊
You seem to know how to drink your wine.
我喜歡的東西不多  但確實很喜歡紅酒
I indulge in few things, but I do love wine.
你呢
Yourself?
我還能喝的時候很喜歡
In my other life, when I could drink for one.
但就算那時我品味也挺差的
But even then I had cheap tastes.
聞聞不要緊
It's safe to smell, though.
伸鼻子進去聞聞
Put your nose in there.
我聞著跟別的酒沒什么區別
You know, to me, it smells like every wine.
但我很想學學
But I'd love to learn.
干紅果  鮮紫羅蘭
Dried red fruit, fresh violet,
檸檬皮
uh, lemon peel.
再試試
Try it again.
好好聞  好好想
Smell and really-- really think about it.
我是聞得到檸檬
Mmm, I do smell lemon.
-莎朗  -怎么
- Sharon? - Yeah?
你嫁給這種人怎么沒悶死啊
How do you not blow your brains out being married to him?
什么
Excuse me?
要我再重復一次嗎
Shall I repeat the question?
你是我們的客人
You're a guest in our house.
我是位誠實的客人
A very honest one.
我就錯把你的話當作沒品的笑話
I think I'll mistake what you said as a joke in poor taste
然后起身去洗手間了
and excuse myself to the bathroom.
我這邊還有瓶不錯的陳釀
I have a beautiful vintage over here.
我給你看看牌子
I would love to just show you the label.
我看看
Let's see here.
不對
Nope.
就是這個
There's the one.
這是我最珍貴的珍藏
This is my prized possession, actually.
看看吧
Take a look at this.
我在用
I'm in here.
有事嗎
Can I help you?
今晚很愉快  多謝了
Thank you for a lovely evening.
大獲全勝
Siege in stormstout!
殺敵無數
Carcass emblem!
我們有麻煩了
We got problems.
樹莓派上線了嗎
Is the pi online?
嗯  我們侵入了整個系統了
Yeah, we're in the whole system.
只要我們想  可以馬上植入病毒
We could deliver the whole payload right now if we wanted.
但卻沒有鼓掌聲
And yet I hear no applause.
鼓掌
Applaud.
你得告訴他們
You have to tell them.
怎么了
What?
我們失去了中國那邊
We lost China.
什么
I'm sorry?
黑暗軍團不干了
The Dark Army is bailing.
為什么
Why?
看來他們不提供解釋
They don't answer whys apparently.
沒事  我們把他們叫回來就行
That's no problem. We'll just call 'em back.
盡快再安排一次見面
We'll set up another meet asap--
伙計  你沒聽到嗎
Dude, did you not hear me?
他們已經消失了  不可能了
They've gone dark. It's not happening.
我知道
I know. I know.
我知道  我搞砸了
I get it, okay? I f---ed up.
夏拉
我們別等了
Let's not wait, then.
我們動手吧  就我們自己
Let's do it anyway, just us.
我們馬上就動手
Let's do it right now.
好嗎  我們馬上執行
Okay? We execute now.
我們自己執行  寄希望于黑暗軍團
We execute on our side and trust that the Dark Army
能振作起來  跟上步伐
gets their shit together and follows.
憑什么讓他們決定啊
Why do they get to dictate terms?
該我們來決定
We dictate terms!
我們可以馬上開始
We can go now.
如果我們行動了  而他們沒有
If we move forward and they don't,
中國那邊還是有全部冗余備份
China still holds all the redundant information.
那就毫無意義了
It will be pointless.
如果我們等  也就沒戲了
And if we wait, it'll also be pointless.
你們今天做的一切都白費了
Everything you guys did today would be for nothing.
天吶  你瘋了嗎
God, are you crazy?
那樣毫無效力
It will have no effect!
能搞垮他們的網絡數周
It'll take down their network for weeks.
他們會恢復的
They'll recover.
還是能傷到他們
It would still hurt them.
我們不想傷他們
We don't want to hurt them!
我們想殺了他們
We want to kill them!
如果我們現在無所作為這兩樣都別指望了
And neither will happen if we do nothing right now.
你干什么呢
What are you doing, huh?
再走一步我就動手了
Take another step, and I'll do it.
好好想想你在做什么
Think about what you're doing, okay?
好嗎
All right?
只需要一個月  他們就又能重新運轉了
In a month, they're gonna be up and running again
而且安保會更好
with even better security.
我們再也不會有第二次機會了
We are not gonna get another shot at this.
我們一直在說的革命
The revolution that we've always talked about
就完蛋了  沒戲了
will be gone, dead, and buried.
我們會因為你  而失敗
We will have failed because of you.
別這么做
Please do not do this.
你們有誰能跟這女人說理嗎
Is there anyone here who can communicate with this woman?
求你
Please.
告訴我可以執行
Tell me it's okay to execute.
但我們就差一點了啊
But we were so close.
沒有結束
It's not over.
我們重新研究
We'll rework it.
我們會想到辦法的
We'll figure something out.
我們都走到這一步了
We got this far.
我們會找到辦法的  只是不是今晚
We'll find a way, just not tonight.
這都怪我
This is all my fault.
行了
Come on.
你可以去我家睡
You can crash at my place.
我父親有一天去學校接我
My father picked me up from school one day,
我們翹課  去了海灘
and we played hooky and went to the beach.
水太冷  不能下去
It was too cold to go in the water,
我們就坐在一塊毯子上吃披薩
so we sat on a blanket and ate pizza.
我回到家后  鞋里都是沙子
When I got home, my sneakers were full of sand,
我都倒在臥室地板上了
and I dumped it on my bedroom floor.
我當時也不懂事
I didn't know the difference.
我才6歲
I was six.
我媽媽為我弄得那么臟大吼我
My mother screamed at me for the mess,
逾期未付
但他卻不生氣
But he wasn't mad.
他說數十億年前
He said that billions of years ago,
世界變遷  滄海桑田
the world shifting and the oceans moving
才把那粒沙子帶上了那片海灘
brought that sand to that spot on the beach,
然后卻被我帶走了
and then I took it away.
他說  "每天
"Every day," He said,
我們都會改變世界"  想想還挺不錯的
"We change the world," which is a nice thought
逾期未付金額
E公司保險
但我又想到  我要花幾輩子
until I think about how many days and lifetimes
揣一鞋的沙子回家
I would need to bring a shoe full of sand home
海灘才會消失
until there is no beach,
才會真正影響任何人
until it made a difference to anyone.
每一天  我們都改變世界
Every day, we change the world,
但如果想做出任何有意義的改變
but to change the world in a way that means anything,
這需要大部分人沒有的時間
that takes more time than most people have.
而且從不會一下就做到
It never happens all at once.
這過程很慢
It's slow.
有條不紊
It's methodical.
讓人疲憊
It's exhausting.
不是每個人都能承受得住
We don't all have the stomach for it.
親愛的
Hey, sweetie.
我去跑個步
I'm gonna go for a run.
好
Nice.
狗在夏拉那里
Shayla's got the dog.
她不在她枕頭上拉屎
She doesn't shit on her pillows.
那算是好事吧
That's a plus, I guess.
夏拉
Shayla?
伙計
Hey, brah.
有時候  宇宙的安排真奇妙
Sometimes the universe aligns perfectly.
我被關在這里
Here I am, locked away.
它卻還是能帶你來找我
Still, it brings you right to me.